A Guide to the Leo Wardrup Papers, 1990-2007
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Leo Wardrup Papers, 1990-2007
The Library of Virginia
43674
1.35 cu. ft. (3 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Leo Wardrup, Virginia Beach, March 2008.
Biographical Information
Leo Wardrup was born 5 September 1936 in Middlesboro, Kentucky and attended the University of North Carolina and George Washington University. He served in the Navy as captain and moved to Virginia Beach to be controller at Oceana Naval Air Station, retiring in 1986. He joined Tidewater Consultants Inc. as a financial analyst and consultant. In 1990 he ran an unsuccessful bid for Virginia Beach City Council. In 1992 he was elected to the Virginia House of Delegates as a Republican in the 83rd District (Virginia Beach) and served until he retired in 2007. During his sixteen years in the House of Delegates, Wardrup served on the Appropriations, Transportation, and Rules Committees.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1990-2007, of Leo Wardrup, former member of the Virginia House of Delegates from the 83rd District, encompassing part of Virginia Beach. Includes campaign literature, correspondence, newspaper clippings, copies of bills and related legislation. Topics include the Chesapeake Bay Bridge Tunnel, U.S. Route 460, interstate maintenance, zoning, and light rail.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- Campaign literature, 1990-2000. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, Constituent, 2001-2002. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, Constituent, 2003-2005. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Constituent, 2006-2007. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Official, 2001-2002. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, Official, 2004-2005. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, Official, 2006. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Legislation, 1996, Alanton Sewer Project. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Legislation, 1998, HB 1244, Sand Dunes. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Legislation, 2002, HB 4, HOV Lanes. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Legislation, 2003, HB 1461, Motor Vehicle Ops by Visually Impaired Persons. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Legislation, 2003, HB 1660, Personal Flotation Devices. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Legislation, 2003, HB 1737, Lymphedema. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Legislation, 2004, HB 898, Homeowners Insurance. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Legislation, 2004, HB 899, Registration of Golf Carts and Utility Vehicles. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Legislation, 2004, HB 902, Tax Filing by Commissioners of Revenue. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Legislation, 2005, HJR 677, Commending Curley Weber. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Legislation, 2006, HB 665, Vegetation Control. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Legislation, 2006, HB 667, Interstate Maintenance. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Legislation, 2006, HJR 75, U.S. Route 460 Committee. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Legislation, 2007, HB 2203, Subaqueous Land to Moon of Norfolk, LLC. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Legislation, 2007, HB 2204, Special Grand Juries. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Legislation, 2007, HB 2224, "BPOL" Tax. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Legislation, 2007, HB 3157, Candidate Filing Requirements. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Legislation, 2007, LD 1519, Abolition of State Compensation Board. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Newspaper Clippings, Campaign articles, 1991-2002. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Newspaper Clippings, Campaign articles, 2003-2007. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Newspaper Clippings, Editorials, 1999-2007. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Photographs, 2007. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Special Projects, Board of Zoning Appeals, 1998. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Special Projects, Chesapeake Bay Bridge Tunnel, 1997-2006. (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- Special Projects, JLARC [Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission], 2002-2003. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Special Projects, Light Rail, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Special Projects, Marine Resource Commission, 1997. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Special Projects, U.S. Route 460, 2005. (Box 3, Folder 6)